Register of the Charles Maynard Cooke papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Charles Maynard Cooke papers
1920-1964
68005
Hoover Institution Archives
37 manuscript boxes, 2 envelopes (17.8 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, dispatches, memoranda, and photographs relating to American naval operations in World War II, inter-Allied diplomacy in World War II, the defenses of Taiwan, and American domestic and foreign policy. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Cooke, Charles Maynard, 1886-1970.
Access
Box 36 closed. Eligible to be opened in 2025. Remainder of collection is open for research. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1968.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Biographical Note
1886 December 19 Born, Fort Smith, Arkansas
1905 B.S., University of Arkansas
1906-1910 Midshipman, U.S. Naval Academy
1912 Commissioned, Ensign
1913-1916 Submarine duty
1915 Promoted to the rank of Lieutenant (junior grade)
1916-1918 Assistant Inspector of Machinery, Fore River Shipbuilding Corporation
1917 Naval member, First Naval District Section of Joint Army and Navy Survey of Merchant Vessels
1918 Promoted to the rank of Lieutenant
1921 Promoted to the rank of Lieutenant Commander
1923 Superintendant and Engineer Officer, Naval Station, Cavite, Philippine Islands
1929 Promoted to the rank of Commander
1931 Promoted to the rank of Captain
1931-1933 Commander, Submarine Division Eleven, Pearl Harbor, Hawaii
1934-1937 Commandant, Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba
1936-1938 Fleet War Plans and Logistics Officer, U.S. Fleet
1938-1941 Staff, War Plans Division, Office of the Chief of Naval Operations
1941 Commanding officer, U.S.S. Pennsylvania
1942 Promoted to the rank of Rear Admiral
1942-1944 Deputy Chief of Staff, U.S. Fleet
1944 Promoted to the rank of Vice Admiral
1944-1945 Chief of Staff to the Commander-in-Chief, U.S. Fleet (Deputy Chief of Naval Operations)
1945 Distinguished Service Medal
1946 Promoted to the rank of Admiral
1946-1948 Commander, Seventh Fleet, Western Pacific (U.S. Naval Force, Western Pacific)
1948 Transfered to the Retired List of the Navy
1950-1951 Coordinator, Commerce International China, Special Technician Program (STP) to the Republic of China (Taiwan); unofficial advisor to the government of Chiang Kai-shek
1957-1961 Director, Ingalls Taiwan Shipbuilding and Dry Dock Company
1970 December 24 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, dispatches, memoranda, and photographs relating to American naval operations in World War II, inter-Allied diplomacy in World War II, the defenses of Taiwan, and American domestic and foreign policy.
Chiang, Kai-shek, 1887-1975.; United States. Navy--Officers.; World War, 1939-1945--Diplomatic history.; World War, 1939-1945--Naval operations.; Taiwan--Defenses.; United States--Foreign relations--1945-1989.; United States--Politics and government--1945-1989.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1928-1964 (Boxes 1-9)
  Arrangement note
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - General (Box 1)
  - Unidentified
  - Adams, Mary (Mrs. W. J. B.), 1937
  - Admas, Mary Luce, 1956
  - Adamkiewicz, L. L., 1948
  - Ainsworth, Commander W. L. (Pug), 1936-1937
  - Aircraft Industries Association of America, Inc.; L. D. Webb, 1948
  - Aitcheson, Inc., 1941
  - Alden, Florence, 1962
  - Alexander, Commander J. T. (Alek), 1937-1938
  - Alford, Lieutenant Commander L. O., 1933
  - Allen, Commander Arthur A., 1949
  - Allien (Henry V.) & Co., 1936
  - American Bureau for Medical Aid to China; George E. Armstrong, 1962
  - American Legion (Department of Illinois); Karl Yost, 1962
  - American Oil Company (South Washington, Va.), 1930
  - Anderson, Admiral George W., 1961
  - Anderson, Rear Admiral W. S., 1942
  - Andrews, Rear Admiral Adolphus, 1934-1942
  - Andrews, Rear Admiral Philip, 1931
  - Ansel, Walter, 1950
  - Arkansas (University of) Alumni Association, 1930
  - Armstrong, Congressman O. K., 1951, 1953
  - Army & Navy Country Club (Washington, D.C.), 1936
  - Army & Navy Journal, 1931
  - Army & Navy Register, 1931, 1941
  - Austin, Captain M. H.; Office of the Chief of Naval Operations, Progress Analysis Group, 1958
  - Bacardi, Antonio, 1934-1935
  - Bacardi, Joaquin, 1934-1935
  - Badger, Rear Admiral Oscar, 1944-1946
  - Bagley, Rear Admiral D. W., 1941
  - Baker, Commander Wilder D., 1938
  - Ballentine, Lieutenant Commander J. J., 1937
  - Ballentine, Captain John, 1942
  - Barrett, Brigadier General C. D. (Charlie), 1942
  - Barrett, Paul L., 1942
  - Barry, Commander J. R., 1935
  - Bartholomew, Frank H.; United Press International, 1955, 1963
  - Batista, Colonel Fulgencio, Cuba, 1936
  - Beary, Commander D. B. (Red), 1930, 1937
  - Bechler, Elfriede, 1946-1947
  - Bell, Arthur F., 1960
  - Bennett, Claude; Bellvue-Stratford Hotel (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1936
  - Benson, Captain H. H. J. (Howard), 1938
  - Berguelich, C. B., 1936
  - Bieri, Commander B. H. (Bernhart), 1931, 1948
  - Blandin, J. J. (Ducky); Goodyear Tire and Rubber Co., 1938-1939, 1947
  - Blandy, Commander W. H. P. (Spike), 1936-1937, 1948
  - Bloch, Admiral C. C., 1937
  - Bode, Captain Howard D., 1932-1933, 1936-1937, 1942
  - Boone, Rear Admiral W. F. (Fred), 1947, 1950
  - Bowman, Commander M. C., 1937
  - Bowman, Commander R. L., 1942
  - Boyd, Vice Admiral, Sir Denis, Great Britain, 1947
  - Bozell, L. Brent; Committee for the Goldwater Book, 1960
  - Bradley, Major General Follett, 1948
  - Brandt, Karl E., 1957
  - Brashears, Lieutenant Commander G. W., 1937
  - Brekken, Mrs. A. B., 1942
  - Bright, Captain Clarkson, 1942
  - Broadbent, Commander E. W., 1936-1937
  - Brooke, Lieutenant G. M., 1932
  - Brow, Lieutenant Commander Harold J., 1938
  - Brown, Commander M. S. (Chub), 1935
  - Brown, Lieutenant Colonel R. Duncan, 1936
  - Browning, Lieutenant Commander Miles R., 1938, 1941-1942
  - Brucker, Secretary of War Wilber M., 1958
  - Brumby, Rear Admiral F. H., 1936
  - Bryan, David Tennant, 1948
  - Buckmaster, Commander Elliott, 1937
  - Buell, Raymond Leslie, 1941
  - Bullitt, William C., 1951
  - Bunkley, Captain J. W., 1941
  - Burke, Admiral Arleigh, 1956, 1958-1961
  - Burnside, Lieutenant J. L., 1931
  - Burrough, Captain E. W. (Ed), 1942
  - Byrd, Rear Admiral Richard E., 1947-1948
  - Caffery, Ambassador (to Cuba) Jefferson, 1936 (Box 2)
  - Cain, Senator Harry, 1951
  - Calhoun, Rear Admiral W. L. (Bill), 1938, 1942, 1948
  - Carney, Robert B. (Mick), 1942
  - Carpenter, Rear Admiral A. S. (Chips), 1942, 1948
  - Carroll, Captain P. L. (Pen), 1936, 1942
  - Carter, Captain W. R. (Nick), 1936, 1941
  - Cecil (Hotel) (San Francisco, Ca.), 1937
  - Chen, Cheng, Vice President and Prime Minister of the Republic of China, 1947, 1954, 1961-1962
  - Chen, Mrs. Pearl, 1958
  - Cheng, Kai-ming, Vice Minister of National Defense, China, 1947
  - Chennault, General Claire, 1950
  - Chen-yi, General, China, 1946
  - Chesterton, A. K., 1962
  - Chiang, Kai-shek, President of the Republic of China, 1947, 1950-1951, 1953-1954, 1956-1957, 1959-1960
  - Chiang, Madame Kai-shek (Soong May-ling), 1947-1948, 1952, 1957, 1959-1961, undated
  - China, Republic of. Embassy, Paris; M. L. Tuan, 1952
  - China, Republic of. Consulate General, San Francisco; Patrick P. Sun, 1958
  - China. Salt Administration - Shantung District; C. G. G. Pearson, 1947
  - China House Association; C. H. Lowe, 1955
  - China Merchants Steam Navigation Co., Ltd., 1951
  - China Tiffin Club; W. Dalton Davis, 1958
  - Chrysler Corporation, 1937
  - Church, Captain A. T., 1936-1937
  - Churchill, Winston, Prime Minister of Great Britain; J. R. Colville, 1944
  - Churchill, Mrs. Winston (Clementine S.), 1944
  - Clark, Bob, undated
  - Clark, Lieutenant Commander D. E., 1946
  - Clark, Mrs. Frances Anne, 1937
  - Clay, General Lucius D., 1947
  - Clifton, Guy L., 1936
  - Cobey, Captain E. A., 1942
  - Coblentz, E. D. (Cobbie); San Francisco Call-Bulletin, 1950-1951, 1955
  - Cochrane, E. L., 1948
  - Cole, Rear Admiral W. C., 1931
  - Cole, Congressman W. Sterling, 1953
  - Coll, Lieutenant Commander J. O. L. (Reilly), 1941-1942
  - College Graduates Against Educating Traitors at Government Expense; Harold Bailey, 1960-1961
  - Collier's Magazine; Louis Ruppel, 1949
  - Committee of One Million Against the Admission of Communist China to the United Nations, 1958-1959
  - Committee to Defend America by Aiding Anti-Communist China; Mrs. Geraldine Fitch, 1951
  - Commonwealth Club of California; Stuart R. Ward, 1958
  - Compton, Karl T., 1953
  - Conaghan, Miss Hazel S., 1942
  - Connor, Lieutenant Commander Fred W., 1937
  - Connally, Senator Tom, 1943
  - Connolly, Captain J. A. (Joe), 1946
  - Conolly, Vice Admiral R. L., 1945-1946, 1948, 1952-1953
  - Constitution Party (California); Mrs. Samuel G. (Lena Lee) Clark, 1959
  - Cooke, Alexander, 1931-1932, 1935
  - Cooke, Anne Bleecker, 1934-1937, 1941, 1950, 1960, undated
  - Cooke, Carol, undated
  - Cooke, Charles Maynard, Sr., 1936-1937, 1941-1942, 1946
  - Cooke, Mrs. Charles Maynard, Sr., 1935-1936, undated
  - Cooke, Charles Maynard, Jr. (III), 1950, 1960-1962, undated
  - Cooke, Cornelia P. (Nee), 1934-1935, 1937, 1941
  - Cooke, Elizabeth, 1937
  - Cooke, Captain H. D., 1931
  - Cooke, Commander John B., 1928, 1931-1932, 1936-1937, 1939-1940, 1947-1948, 1959, 1961-1962, undated
  - Cooke, Mary (Mrs. C. M.), 1936-1937
  - Cooke, Mary Maynard, 1937, 1950, 1963
  - Cooke, Lieutenant Commander Stephen B., 1928, 1933-1934, 1936-1937
  - Cooke, William F., 1936, 1959, 1961
  - Cooper, Harry F., 1938
  - Coward (James S.) Shoe Co., 1932
  - Crain, Ralph W., 1937
  - Crayton, Sherman G.; The Torch, 1956
  - Crenshaw, Captain Russell S., 1942
  - Crocker, George N., 1960
  - Crosbie, W. G., 1935
  - Crosby, Captain T. A., Great Britain, 1943
  - Crosley, P. C., 1942
  - Crutchfield, Commander James A., 1935
  - Culp, Captain R. S., 1936
  - Curtis, Senator Carl, 1962
  - Davidson, Commander L. A. (Davy), 1933, 1937 (Box 3)
  - Davidson, Lyal, 1934
  - Davis, Commander Arthur C., 1937
  - Davis, Monnett B., 1946-1948
  - Davis, Commander R. O., 1937, 1948
  - Dawes, Captain R. A., 1937-1938
  - Dean, Lieutenant Commander Frank H., 1932, 1937
  - Deane, Johnny, 1948
  - Defrees, Rear Admiral J. R., 1937
  - Delano, Captain Harvey, 1937
  - Denebrink, Captain F. C., 1937, 1942
  - Denfeld, Admiral Louis E., 1937, 1943, 1947, 1949
  - Desmond's (Long Beach, Ca.), 1936
  - Dessez, Captain J. H. S., 1937
  - Dickey, Lieutenant Commander Fred C., 1938
  - Dickson, George L., 1937, 1948
  - Dollar Steamship Lines (San Francisco, Ca.), 1936
  - Dollard, Captain Henry L., 1935
  - Domingo y Morales del Castillo, Andres, 1936
  - Donelson, Commander John F., 1932
  - Douglas, Senator Paul H., 1951
  - Doyle, Vice Admiral A. K. (Arty), 1957
  - Doyle, Commander T. J., 1936-1937
  - Doyle, Commander Walter E. (Red), 1933, 1937-1938
  - Duncan, Admiral Donald B. (Wu), 1937, 1953
  - DuVal, Miles, 1964
  - Duvall, Jo, 1964
  - Dyer, Lieutenant Commander George C., 1932, 1936-1937
  - Edison, Charles, 1957, 1959
  - Edwards, Admiral R. S., 1937, 1951
  - Eisenhower, President Dwight D., 1952-1953, 1961
  - Eldred, Lieutenant Commander A. W., 1936-1937
  - Eliot, George Fielding, 1962
  - English, Commander R. H. (Bob), 1931-1932, 1935-1937
  - Erck, Lieutenant C. F., 1935
  - Eurasia Travel Service (Taipei, Taiwan), 1951
  - Ewald, Commander J. B., 1936-1937
  - Ewing, Auguste B., 1951
  - Fagan, Louis, 1942
  - Fang, Rear Admiral Yin, China, 1947
  - Field, Major C. F., 1954
  - Fife, Rear Admiral James, 1937, 1945, 1948
  - Fischler, Rear Admiral Pete, 1942, 1948
  - Fisher, John W.; American Security Council, 1962
  - Fitch, Vice Admiral Aubrey W., 1945
  - Fitzgerald, James P., 1957
  - Floyd, Lieutenant William O., 1931
  - Ford, Ellsworth [see: George H. Townsend]
  - Foreign Service Educational Foundation; William C. Schmeisser, Jr., 1953
  - Forrestal, Secretary of the Navy (and Defense) James V., 1946-1949
  - Fort, Commander George H., 1936-1937
  - Freeman, Rear Admiral C. S., 1935
  - Friedell, Captain W. L. (Eph), 1937-1938
  - Galliford, Mae (Mrs. W. T. H.), 1935-1936
  - Gardner, Vice Admiral M. B. (Mat), 1955
  - Ghormley, Captain Robert L., 1938, 1945
  - Glover, Lieutenant Commander R. O., 1931
  - Goldwater, Senator Barry, 1960, 1962, 1964
  - Gordon, Emily Bamford, 1948
  - Gorham Company (Providence, R.I.), 1936
  - Gorry, Lieutenant Commander William A. (Hod), 1935-1937
  - Grant (Ulysses S.) Hotel (San Diego, Ca.); Edward S. Bernard, 1933
  - Graves, Lieutenant E. D., Jr., 1935
  - Gray, General; Veterans Administration, 1949
  - Gray, Commander A. H. (Gus), 1935
  - Great Britain. Consulate General, San Francisco, Ca.; E. W. Meiklereid, 1948
  - Greenslade, Rear Admiral J. W., 1933
  - Greenway, Reverand Cornelius, 1939
  - Gregerson, Magnus I., 1963
  - Griffin, Vice Admiral R. M. (Bob), 1942, 1947
  - Griffith Consumers Company (Washington, D.C.), 1930
  - Grisham, Lieutenant Commander Charles F., 1934-1937, 1939-1940, 1948, undated
  - Guild, Captain Eugene R., 1955 (Box 4)
  - Gulf Refining Co. (Rosslyn, Va.), 1930
  - Guy, George Frederick, 1952
  - Gwan, Terry, 1959
  - Gygax, Captain Felix X., 1938
  - Haase, Mrs. Walter, 1942
  - Haislip, H. S.; Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Corporation, 1936
  - Hamel, Lieutenant L. S., 1936
  - Hanan & Son Shoes (Los Angeles, Ca.), 1936
  - Hancock, Joy Bright (Mrs. Lewis), 1942
  - Handy, General Thomas T., 1948
  - Hardison, By, 1946
  - Harriman, Secretary of Commerce W. Averill, 1949
  - Hart, Rear Admiral Thomas C., 1934
  - Hawaiian Electric Co., 1932
  - Hawes, Francesca, 1937
  - Haygood, General Johnson, 1940
  - Healy, Lieutenant Commander H. R., 1938
  - Hearst, Randolph A., 1950
  - Hearst, William R., Jr., 1954
  - Hede, Lieutenant Adolph (Al), 1935, 1937
  - Heffernan, Captain John B., 1942
  - Hein, Commander H. R. (Hop), 1931, 1938-1939
  - Helm, Captain Jesse B. (Jay), 1937
  - Hepburn, Rear Admiral A. J., 1934, 1936, 1938
  - Hersey, Captain Mark L., Jr., 1935-1938
  - Hewitt, Captain H. Kent, 1937-1938, 1948
  - Hicks, Lieutenant Commander W. A.; Navy Department, Bureau of Navigation, Officer Detail Section, 1932-1933
  - Hill, Captain, Harry W., 1934, 1938-1939, 1942, 1948
  - Hill, Judge Joseph M., 1930
  - Hoffman, Congressman Clare E., 1953
  - Hoffman, Lieutenant Commander Harry D., 1937
  - Holcomb, Lieutenant General Thomas, 1942
  - Holden, Rear Admiral Carl F., 1942, 1948
  - Holloway, Rear Admiral J. L., 1948
  - Honolulu Chamber of Commerce, 1932
  - Hooker, Commander J. F., 1937
  - Hornbeck, Stanley K., 1956
  - Horowitt, Julius, 1942
  - Hoskins, H. C., 1932
  - Hou, Lieutenant General Fisher T., Republic of China, 1953
  - Howard, Roy; Scripps-Howard Newspapers, 1949
  - Hsieh, Jen-chao, 1959
  - Hsueh, Yueh, 1950
  - Huang, General J. L., Republic of China, 1951
  - Huang, Siu feng, 1949
  - Huang, S. K., Minister of Foreign Affairs, Republic of China, 1959
  - Hudson, Captain M. F., 1942, undated
  - Hughes Hallett, Vice Admiral Cecil, Great Britain, 1953
  - Ingersoll, Vice Admiral R. E., 1938, 1942
  - International Mark Twain Society; Cyril Clemens, 1944
  - International News Service; Barry Faris, 1950
  - Izac, Congressman Ed V., 1947
  - Jackson, Senator Henry M., 1961
  - Jacobs, Captain Randall, 1936
  - Jen Ai Children's Home; Taipei International Women's Club, 1953-1954
  - Jersey, Commander Chester C., 1936-1937
  - Jessup, Ambassador-at-large Philip C., 1949
  - Johnson, Admiral A. W., 1936
  - Johnson, Captain E. A., 1933
  - Johnson, Helen (Mrs. M. W.), 1936, 1940
  - Johnson, Maynard P., 1939
  - Jones, Chesley, 1931
  - Jones, Lieuenant D. L., 1936
  - Jones, Fred L., 1939
  - Jordon, Commander Leland, 1934
  - Joslin, Hamilton B., 1940
  - Joy, Vice Admiral Charles Turner, 1950, 1952
  - Judd, Congressman Walter H.; Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectuals, Inc.; American-Asian Educational Exchange, Inc.; American Bureau for Medical Aid to China, 1952-1954, 1958-1962
  - Jungbluth, O. J., 1935
  - Juvenal, W. W., 1946
  - Kane, R. Keith, 1948
  - Kauffman, Vice Admiral J. L. (Reg), 1948
  - Keating, J. S., 1948
  - Kempff, Rear Admiral C. S., 1934
  - Kidd, I. C., 1934
  - Kilpatrick, Captain W. K., 1942
  - Kimmel, Admiral Husband E., 1960-1961
  - King, Fleet Admiral Ernest J., 1942, 1945-1946, 1948-1950
  - King, Samuel W., 1931
  - Kinkaid, Admiral Thomas C., 1934-1936, undated
  - Kirk, Captain Alan G. (Bill), 1937, 1942, 1962
  - Knowland, Senator William F., 1950-1951, 1954
  - Kohlberg, Alfred and Ida; Alfred Kohlberg, Inc.; American China Policy Association; Citizens Foreign Relations Committee, miscellaneous, 1949-1961 (Box 5)
    Scope and Contents note
    Contains copies of numerous letters from Kohlberg to third parties.
  - Krause (Fred W.) Agency, 1937 (Box 6)
  - Kubeck, Anthony, 1960
  - Kwei, C. S., 1953-1954
  - Kwei, General Yun-chin, Republic of China, 1947, 1950-1954
  - Ladd, Lieutenant Colonel Jesse A., 1937
  - Lademan, Joseph U., Jr., 1950-1951
  - Land, Rear Admiral E. S. (Jerry), 1936-1937, 1942
  - Laning, Captain Richard B., 1960
  - Lansdale, Maria H., 1934
  - Lauman, Commander P. G. (Phil), 1935
  - Lawrence, Raymond; Oakland Tribune, 1954-1955
    Correspondence with Shih-chi Wu attached.
  - Leahy, Fleet Admiral William D., 1953
  - Leary, Captain Herbert F., 1937
  - Lee, K. S., 1957
  - LeTang, Linus L., 1957
  - Leverton, Captain J. W., Jr., 1958
  - Lewis, Fulton, Jr., 1955
  - Lewis, Captain H. K., 1942
  - Li, Colonel David, Republic of China, 1950
  - Li, Sien-liang, 1948, 1955-1956
  - Li, Dr. Ti-tsun, Chinese Ambassador to Turkey, 1952
  - Liang, Admiral Hsu-chao, Republic of China, 1956
  - Liberty Lobby, undated
  - Liebman, Marvin; Committee of One Million; American-Asian Educational Exchange, Inc.; American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees, 1957, 1959-1960, 1962
  - Lincoln, G. A. (Abe), 1948
  - Lind, Commander W. L., 1934
  - Lindsay, Commander L. E. (Cardinal), 1937
  - Litchfield-Speer, Captain J. S. S., Great Britain, 1946
  - Little, Brigadier General Louis M., 1934
  - Liu, Rear Admiral Hoh Tu, Republic of China, 1956, 1962
  - Lockwood, C. A., Jr., 1942
  - Loder, Commander Ames, 1937
  - Loeb, William, 1963
  - London, Captain J. J., 1935
  - Longstaff, Lieutenant John B., 1931
  - Longstaff, Vee (Mrs. John B.), 1937
  - Low, Vice Admiral F. S., 1937, 1948, 1954
  - Lowe, A. B., undated
  - Lowe, Commander Loper, 1936-1937
  - Lowry, Rear Admiral F. J., 1948
  - Luce, Bill, 1945
  - Luce, Charlotte, 1936
  - Luce, Henry R.; Time and Life, 1952, 1961
  - Luckel, Commander Frank, 1937, 1942
  - Lynch, Robert M., 1962
  - Ma, Chi Chuang, 1952
  - MacArthur, General Douglas, 1947, 1950, 1952
  - McCandlish, Bain V., 1937, 1948
  - McClean, Lieutenant Commander H. H. (Tex), 1935, 1937
  - McCormick, Vice Admiral Lynde D., 1942, 1948
  - McCrea, John, 1948
  - McElroy, C. W., 1921
  - McElroy, Secretary of Defense G. W.; Charles A. Coolidge, 1958
  - MacFarlane, Scott Bartlett, undated
  - McGee, William, 1948
  - MacMillan, Alexander, 1936-1937, 1946
  - MacMillan Company, 1953
  - MacMillan, Sally Willoughby, 1946
  - Mandel, Benjamin; U.S. Senate, Committee on the Judiciary, Internal Security Subcommittee, 1960
  - Manly, Captain M. E., 1935
  - Manor Club (Washington, D.C.), 1928
  - Mansfield, Congressman Mike, 1947
  - Markham, Sir Henry V., Secretary of the Admiralty, Great Britain, 1946
  - Marshall, Ed, 1948
  - Marshall, Secretary of State George C., 1946-1948
  - Mayhew, Dorothy Ford, 1945
  - Mechem, Edwin, 1941
  - Merwin, Davis, 1961
  - Miles, Rear Admiral Milton E., 1951
  - Miller, L. H., 1934
  - Minute Women of the U. S. A., Anita Phister, 1960
  - Mitscher, Commander M. A., 1938
  - Molinet, Elise (Mrs. Joaquin), 1934
  - Montgomery, George S., Jr., 1957
  - Moon, Carl; Brookings Institution, 1942, 1948
  - Moore, Lieutenant Commander C. G., 1936
  - Moore, Rear Admiral C. J. (Charlie), 1937, 1942, 1963
  - Morand, Commander C. G., 1945
  - Morgan, Gail, 1936
  - Morgan, R. E., 1942
  - Moreell, Admiral Ben, 1942, 1961
  - Morison, Samuel E., 194-
  - Morris, Lieutenant Commander Earl W. (Crusty), 1937
  - Mountbatten, Admiral Lord Louis, 1943-1944
  - Mudgett, Katherine (Mrs. William A.), 1958
  - Murphy, Rear Admiral M. E., 1952
  - Murphy, Captain V. R., 1940, 1942
  - Murray, Lieutenant Commander Chauncey R., 1936
  - Murray, Lieutenant Commander S. S. (Sunshine), 1936-1937
  - Naquin, Lieutenant Oliver F., 1940 (Box 7)
  - Nash, Ernest T., 1949-1953, undated
  - National Cyclopedia of American Biography, 1955
  - National Geographic Society, 1944
  - National Majestic Radio & Electric Company, 1939
  - National War College, 1956
  - Naval Clothing Depot (Brooklyn, N.Y.), 1947
  - Naval Historical Foundation, 1948
  - Naval Order of the United States, General Commandery, 1947
  - Navy Ball Committee, Biltmore Hotel (Los Angeles, Ca.), 1933
  - Navy Relief Society; Admiral J. O. Richardson, 1944
  - Need, Lieutenant Commander Harry W., 1937
  - Nelson, Walter, 1942
  - New York Herald-Tribune, 1936-1937
  - Newsweek Magazine, 1960
  - Newton, Captain John Henry, 1937
  - Ni, Admiral Yue-si, Republic of China, 1952, 1961
  - Nicholson, Lieutenant Commander T. A., 1940, 1942
  - Nielson, Lorena, 1937
  - Nimitz, Fleet Admiral Chester W., 1946-1947, 1962
  - Nixon, Commander E. B. (Nick), 1935
  - Nixon, Vice President Richard M., 1958, 1960
  - Norman, Lieutenant Commander R. G., 1942
  - Noyes, Charlotte Luce (Mrs. Boutelle), 1936-1937, 1940, 1945, undated
  - Noyes, Pauline (Mrs. R. B.), 1938-1942
  - Odlin, Commander L. A., 1936
  - Ogan, Captain J. V., 1938
  - Olsen, Rear Admiral C. E., 1944
  - Orem, Captain Howard, 1950
  - Orville, Commander H. T., 1942
  - Osborne, John; Life Magazine, 1952
  - Osment, William; Guantanamo & Western Railroad Co., 1934-1936
  - Osterhaus, Rear Admiral Hugo W., 1936-1937
  - Ostermann, Colonel E. A., 1934-1937
  - Ouang, Max and Eppie, 1948
  - Pace, Lieutenant Commander Leo L., 1935-1937
  - Pacific Coast Club, 1937
  - Painter, William L., 1946-1947
  - Palma, Jose, 1935
  - Pan American Airways; Colonel Clarence Young, 1937
  - Parks, Doris (Mrs. Benjamin S.), 1958, 1961-1962
  - Parsons, Lieutenant Commander W. S. (Deak), 1936-1938
  - Paul, Edith (Mrs. W. W.), 1936, 1940
  - Pearson, Mr. and Mrs. Roy R., 1947
  - Peel, J., 1947
  - Persons, Rear Admiral H. S., 1958
  - Peterson, Lieutenant Commander E. B. (Pete), 1937
  - Pfeiffer, Colonel O. T. (Omar), 1942
  - Pinkerton, C. F., 1951
  - Pond, T. E., 1934
  - Popham, Captain and Mrs. W. S. (Bill and Louisa), 1942
  - Portsmouth, Va. Chamber of Commerce, 1943
  - Possony, Stefen T., 1960
  - Pownall, Commander Charles A. (Baldy), 1938